

# **Summary**

Experienced full-stack engineer with over 4 years in development and technical leadership, specializing in solving complex problems, delivering scalable solutions, and optimizing infrastructure. Seeking to bring expertise to a technical engineering role in the Dallas-Fort Worth area.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

### **The Vanguard Group**

Hybrid - Malvern, PA

SOFTWARE TECHNICAL LEAD

Aug. 2023 - Current

- Oversee the technical delivery of a full stack team using AEM and Angular, managing Vanguard Americas FAS secure and public sites.
- Review pull requests, contribute to system architecture and implementation, develop new features and tools, write automation scripts, and address security vulnerabilities.
- Lead strategic planning and team upskilling initiatives to ensure high-quality, secure software delivery.

#### FULL STACK ENGINEER - TECHNOLOGY LEADERSHIP PROGRAM

Nov. 2022 - Aug. 2023

- Developed a serverless secure site that handles registration, and login for Americas investor sites.
- Led development of reporting infrastructure and data lake, enabling the business to perform client analysis.
- Managed and enhanced investor sites by developing new features, integrating with GraphQL APIs, and building new components, resulting in an improved user experience and increased product offerings.

#### DEVOPS CLOUD ENGINEER - TECHNOLOGY LEADERSHIP PROGRAM

Apr. 2022 - Nov. 2022

- Supported 5000+ containerized business applications by completing feature and escalated tickets, ensuring the smooth functioning of critical business operations and enhancing developer effeciency.
- Contributed to the enhancement of the ECS platform's stability and reliability by reducing cloud dependencies, optimizing resource utilization, and implementing best practices for container orchestration.
- Engineered a cloud-native platform insights tool that helped product teams and clients optimize their ECS costs, resulting in significant cost savings and improved resource utilization.

### BACKEND ENGINEER - TECHNOLOGY LEADERSHIP PROGRAM

Aug. 2021 - Apr. 202.

- Developed Java Rest APIs that served internal consumers, specifically APIs that delivered financial fund data. Optimized queries and algorithms to decrease response times and improve application performance.
- Designed and implemented cloud-native ETL jobs and event-driven microservice architecture.
- Retired, refactored and condensed multiple REST APIs saving around 50000 USD a year.

Pfizer Remote - Collegeville, PA

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jun. 2020 - Dec. 2020

- · Contributed to a web based micro-service data processing platform that is utilized by finance and manufacturing teams.
- Engineered a full stack web application that dynamically updates API documentation with latest releases of a set of micro-services.
- · Designed a front-end user interface using individual React components and built out a back-end that exposes a spring boot rest API.

### Education

## The Pennsylvania State University

State College, PA

Jun. 2018 - May. 2021

B.S. IN INFO SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY, FOCUS IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

• Minor: Security and Risk Analysis

- GPA: Cumulative 3.89, Major GPA 4.0
- Accolades: Deans list every year, Richard C. Assetto, Robert and Tammy Morgan Trustee, and Hendrickson Family Trustee Scholarship
- Leadership: President and Co-Founder of Emerging Technology Club
- Java Learning Assistant, Learning Assistant Coordinator, and Security Instructional Assistant

## Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: JAVA, PYTHON, TYPESCRIPT/JAVASCRIPT, SQL, BASH SCRIPTING

WEB TECHNOLOGIES: REACT, ANGULAR, SASS, EXPRESS, NEST.JS, STATE MANAGMENT (NGRX, REACT), WEB COMPONENTS

**TOOLS:** GIT, DOCKER, NGINX, KONG, SPRINGBOOT, MONGODB, POSTMAN, MAVEN, VARIOUS TESTING FRAMEWORKS

**OTHER RELEVANT SKILLS:** AWS, CI/CD (GITHUB ACTIONS/BAMBOO), CDNs, Infrastructure Management, Caching